<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spencer C.H. Barrett on Spencer Barrett</title>
    <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spencer C.H. Barrett on Spencer Barrett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 17:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spencerbarrett.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Research</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/current/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/current/</guid>
      <description>Research Projects in the SCH Barrett Lab Here is some of the research currently being undertaken in the Barrett lab with background and the particular projects that I have funding to support. Students or PDFs that are interested in these topics and who would like to work in my lab should contact me by e-mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Research Visit to China</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/blog/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/blog/post/</guid>
      <description>Spencer C.H. Barrett  Referenced   Professor
Department of Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology
University of Toronto</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Evolutionary Transitions in Flowering Plant Reproduction</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/major-ev-trans-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/major-ev-trans-2008/</guid>
      <description>Major Evolutionary Transitions in Flowering Plant Reproduction Special Issue - International Journal of Plant Sciences (2008)
Edited by:S.C.H. Barrett (2008)
Chapman &amp;amp; Hall, New York.
Among plant life-history traits, those that constitute the reproductive system are the most influential in governing macroevolutionary patterns and microevolutionary processes. This fundamental role arises because reproductive mechanisms influence genetic transmission, population genetic structure, selection response and patterns of evolutionary diversification. Flowering plants exhibit striking diversity in reproductive traits with closely related species often possessing different pollination and mating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/photos/</guid>
      <description>Photo Collections  Plants plants that we work on and others that caught my fancy. People a collection of images of biologists including lab alumni, collaborators and colleagues. Barrett&amp;rsquo;s Lab a collection of pictures of the lab, alumni and research in action. Research a collection of research related pictures. Other a collection of other pictures, including landscapes, travel, etc.   Most of these images were taken with an Olympus Camedia C 750 or C770 Digital Camera by Spencer Barrett.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications Record</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/publications/</guid>
      <description>Historical List of Publications Scientific Publications of Spencer C. H. Barrett.
 Copyright notice: The PDF&amp;rsquo;s below are provided for the dissemination of scholarly research only. The copyrights are retained by the authors and/or publishers and anyone downloading the pdfs is expected to obey the legal requirements imposed by copyright law, and may not repost them without explicit permission from the copyright holder.
 [1975]  Pickersgill, B.P., Barrett, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spencer C.H. Barrett</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>University Professor
Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology
University of Toronto
25 Willcocks Street
Toronto, Ontario, Canada
M5S 3B2
Phone: 416-978-4151
Email: spencer.barrett@utoronto.ca
Degrees  B. Sc. (Honours) Department of Agricultural Botany, University of Reading, England 1967-71
 Ph. D. Department of Botany, University of California, Berkeley, U.S.A. 1972-77 Current Position
 University Professor, University of Toronto, 2008
 Canada Research Chair - Evolutionary Genetics Tier 1 2001-08, 2008-14</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to South Africa</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/blog/post-copy-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/blog/post-copy-1/</guid>
      <description>Spencer C.H. Barrett Professor
Department of Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology
University of Toronto</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecology and Evolution of Flowers</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/ecol-ev-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2006 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/ecol-ev-2006/</guid>
      <description>Ecology and Evolution of Flowers (2006) Editors:
Lawrence D. Harder, University of Calgary
Spencer C. H. Barrett, University of Toronto
Publisher: Oxford University Press, Alpinia (Zingiberaceae)
The reproductive organs and mating biology of angiosperms exhibit greater variety than those of any other group of organisms. Flowers and inflorescences are also the most diverse structures produced by angiosperms, and floral traits provide some of the most compelling examples of evolution by natural selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floral Biology -- on Floral Evolution in Animal-Pollinated Plants</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/foral-bio-1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 1996 13:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/foral-bio-1996/</guid>
      <description>Floral Biology: Studies on Floral Evolution in Animal-Pollinated Plants Editors:
D.G. Lloyd
S.C.H. Barrett
Publisher:
Chapman &amp;amp; Hall, New York.
Studies in floral biology are largely concerned with how flowers function to promote pollination and mating. The role of pollination in governing mating patterns in plant populations inextricably links the evolution of pollination and mating systems. Despite the close functional link between pollination and mating, research conducted for most of this century on these two fundamental aspects of plant reproduction has taken quite separate courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution and Function of Heterostyly</title>
      <link>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/heterostyly-1992/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 1992 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spencerbarrett.ca/research/books/heterostyly-1992/</guid>
      <description>Evolution and Function of Heterostyly (1992) Editors:
Spencer C. H. Barrett
Publisher:
Springer-Verlag, Berlin.
A century of research on heterostylous plants has passed since the publication of Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;The Different Forms of Flowers on Plants of the Same Species&amp;rdquo; in 1877 summarizing his extensive observations and experiments on these complex breeding systems involving genetic polymorphisms of floral sex organs. Since then heterostylous plants have provided a rich source of material for evolutionary biologists and today they represent one of the classic research paradigms for approaches to the study of evolution and adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>